this is a pretty exciting problem you
know about the three four five triangles
you see everywhere in high school
geometry in sa a and even in
construction they show up all over the
place but today what we are going to
show will literally blow up your mind
because if you inscribe a circle in any
three four five triangles then you won't
believe but the area of this inscribed
circle is exactly Pi let us see the math
first let us draw the center of the
circle now draw a radius like this and
this the radius will always be at a
right angle to the tangent point and
therefore this whole thing will become a
square of side length R so this side
will also be R and this side will also
be R now this is three and this is R so
this will be 3 minus r similarly this is
four and this is R so this will be 4 - R
now let us clear out everything and just
keep this circle and these two lines
which are tangent to this circle here
comes the magic the lengths of two
tangent lines drawn from the same
external point to a circle are equal
specifically it is called the two
tangent theorem so this tangent line
will also be 3 minus r and the same
thing goes for this side if this is 4 -
R so this will also be 4 - R now let us
Focus focus on the hypotenuse the length
of the hypotenuse is 5 now this is also
equal to 3 - r + 4 - R so we have 7 - 2
R = 5 this gives 2 R = 2 and R = 1 now
that we have the radius of the circle as
one so what will be the area of this
circle it will be piun * R square and
putting r as 1 we get the area of this
circle as Pi isn't this cool so good